{
    "name": "Impressionism",
    "description": "Impressionism, a revolutionary art movement originating in 19th-century France, celebrated the play of light on everyday scenes. Dive into this set of questions to test your knowledge on iconic Impressionist artists, their masterpieces, and the profound impact they had on the world of art.",
    "flashcards": [
        {
            "question": "Who is considered the \"father\" of Impressionism?",
            "answer": "Claude Monet"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which famous Impressionist painting features Japanese footbridges and water lilies?",
            "answer": "Water Lilies by Claude Monet"
        },
        {
            "question": "What year was the first Impressionist exhibition held?",
            "answer": "1874"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist painted the series of works titled \"Ballet Dancers\"?",
            "answer": "Edgar Degas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Impressionism originated in which country?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Impressionist artist was known for painting scenes of Parisian nightlife and theaters?",
            "answer": "\u00c9douard Manet"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which painting, exhibited in 1874, gave Impressionism its name?",
            "answer": "Impression, Sunrise by Claude Monet"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Impressionist artist is best known for painting scenes of the French countryside?",
            "answer": "Camille Pissarro"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist, although associated with Impressionism, preferred to paint indoors and often depicted family members in his works?",
            "answer": "Pierre-Auguste Renoir"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Impressionist artist had a profound influence on the development of modern art due to his radical use of color and synthetic style?",
            "answer": "Paul C\u00e9zanne"
        }
    ]
}